<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Showcase Template</title><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/</link><description>Recent content on Showcase Template</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-3D-terrain-generation-with-perlin-noise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-3D-terrain-generation-with-perlin-noise/</guid><description>3D Terrain Generation With Perlin Noise # 1. Introduction # In this academic report we are going to develop a 3D Terrain Generator that helps people who are cartographers digitizing representative maps of the world, artists or designers investing their own works, or videogame developers in creating, producing, and generating the necessary maps for the proper development of the video game.
To solve this problem, cartographers, artists, designers and developers use Perlin Noise due its ability to produce more natural-looking patterns of noise and its ability to create complex and varied patterns of noise that looked more natural and organic than previous algorithms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Color-Average/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Color-Average/</guid><description>Color Average
Introduction This application provides a unique way of visualizing and modifying videos by reducing the resolution of the frames to create a pixelated effect.
In addition to pixelation, the application also includes a color averaging feature that takes the average color of each pixel block and applies it to the entire block. This creates a uniform color effect across each block, giving the video a distinctive look.
Literature Review/Background Pixelator Video: A Tutorial on Processing Video in p5.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Color-Blind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Color-Blind/</guid><description>Color Blindness
Introduction In this academic report we are going to develop a color mapping application that helps people who are color blind see the colors around them. To introduce this topic color blindness is a disease that affects a significant percentage of the world&amp;rsquo;s population, about 8% of the male population and 0.5% of women1. It is a genetic disorder that affects the ability to differentiate between certain colors, making it difficult for sufferers to fully experience and appreciate the colors around them.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Moir%C3%A9-Patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Moir%C3%A9-Patterns/</guid><description>Moiré Patterns # 1. Introduction # In mathematics, physics, and art, moiré patterns or moiré fringes are large-scale interference patterns that can be produced when a partially opaque ruled pattern with transparent gaps is overlaid on another similar pattern. For the moiré interference pattern to appear, the two patterns must not be completely identical, but rather displaced, rotated, or have slightly different pitch1.
We decided to study these patterns because of their strong relationship with Masking, a phenomenon of visual perception occurring when the visibility of one image (target) is reduced by the presence of another image (mask)2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Spatial-Coherence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Academic-Report-Spatial-Coherence/</guid><description>Spatial Coherence # 1. Introduction # Spatial coherence is a technique used to preserve the structural integrity of images by retaining the spatial relationships between pixels. The Pixelator video application takes advantage of this technique to create pixelated videos with smooth transitions between frames.
At its core, the pixelator video application uses the power of spatial coherence to analyze and manipulate the pixels in a video stream. This means that as you use the application each pixel is carefully analyzed and manipulated in relation to its surrounding pixels, resulting in a cohesive and visually stunning end result.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Presentation-Video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://VisualComputingDDC.github.io/showcase/docs/shortcodes/visual-illusions/Presentation-Video/</guid><description>Bohemian Rhapsody</description></item></channel></rss>